Tēlemachos Alaveras Papers and Nea Poreia Archives, 1989-2010: Finding Aid C1408
Manuscripts Division
- Series 1: Tēlemachos Alaveras Papers, 1889-2010; 47 boxes; 2 items
  - Subseries 1A: Correspondence, 1924-2010; 14 boxes
    - Philippatos, Leuterēs, 1951-1952; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Hoi Philoi tou Hidrymatos Melina Merkourē [The Friends of the Melina Merkouri Foundation], 1999-2004; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Phiphēs, Chrēstos N., 1988-2004; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Phorēs, Vasileios D., 1990; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Phōstierēs, Antōnēs, 1980-2006; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Phrankopoulos, Th. D., 1959-1982; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Pieridēs, G. Philippou, 1976-1993; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Piompinos, Phoivos I., 1994-2007; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Pittas, Triantaphyllos, 1969-1988; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Plaskovitēs, Spyros, 1960-2000; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Pōgōnitēs, Anthos [or Karaphylēs, Vasilēs], 1948-1949; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Politēs, Linos, 1976; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Polymeroudē, Chrysa, 1991-1998; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Prasinēs, Phōtēs, 1952-1967; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Pratsikas, Geōrgios, 1955-1958; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Pratsikas, Manōlēs, 1955-1989; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Prevelakēs, Pantelēs, 1973-1979; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Public Library of Xanthē (Greece), 1959-1961; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Puchner, Walter, 2003; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Rados, Andreas, 1978-1992; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Raizis, M. Byron, 1982-1985; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Renos [Apostolidēs], 1969-1972; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Rētoridēs, Thalēs, 1956-1957; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Rialto Theatre, 1999-2000; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Rikakēs, Dēmētrēs, 1985; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Ritsos, Giannēs, 1979-1980; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Rizakēs, Kōstas, 1983-2005; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Rodokanakēs, Kōnstantinos Christophoros, 1981-2000; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Rosenthal-Kamarinea, Isidora, 1974-1983; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Roussos, Tasos, 1964-1965; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Ryssianos, Notēs, 1962; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - S (General), 1960-1981; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 16)
      Includes correspondence from: Staphylopatēs, Nikos G.; Sōtērakopoulou, Agnē; Skarimpas, Giannēs; Svolopoulos, Kōnstantinos D.; Steinmetz, Alexander; Savina, Zōe; and Staphylopatēs, Nikos G..
    - Sachinēs, Apostolos, 1978-1992; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Samarakēs, Antōnēs, 1955-1959; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Samouēlidēs, Chrēstos, 1955-2003; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Sangiglio, Cristino, 1968-1985; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Sarantē, Galateia, 1988-2006; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Sartzetakēs, Chrēstos, 1987-2007; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Savvidēs, Geōrgios P., 1955-1984; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Savvidou, Ioanna, 1995; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Schepens, Jan, 1955-1956; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Sēmitēs, Kōstas, 1989-2001; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Sidera-Lytra, Paraskeuē, 2007; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Sinopoulos, Takēs, 1956-1964; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Siōtēs, Dinos, 1986-1989; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Skartsēs, Sōkratēs L. [Ostraka], 1981-2005; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Skatanovits, Takēs, 1995; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Skiadas, Stergios, 1958-1963; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Spandōnidēs, Petros, 1955-1962; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Spanias, Nikos, 1955-1971; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Spentzopoulos, Petros P., 1970-2002; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Sphakianakēs, Giannēs G., 1955-1991; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Spyridōnakēs, V. [Vasilēs], 1970-1972; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - Spyropoulou, Chrysa, 2000-2006; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Stamelos, Dēmētrēs ("Ta Sēmerina"), 1970-2000; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Stamoulēs, Assos, 1992-1995; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Stavrou, Theofanis George, 1984-1985; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Hē Stegē tōn Logotechnōn kai Kallitechnōn Voreiou Hellados [Society for Authors and Artists of Northern Greece], 1959; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Stellakē, Danaē, 1993-1994; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - Stergiopoulos, Kōstas, 1956-1993; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Stogiannidēs, G. X., 1952-1967; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Strasburger, James, 1984-1994; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Stroe, Florian, 1990-1992; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Sveltos, Phōtēs, 2005-2006; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Symposio Neohellēnikēs Poiēsēs-Panepistēmio Patrōn [Poetry Symposium - University of Patras] (See also: Skartsēs, Sōkratēs L.), 1980-2007; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Syndesmos Hellēnōn Logotechnōn [Association of Greek Writers], 1952-1979; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Szyler-Lesiak, Ewa, 1988-1999; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - T (General), 1955-2007; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 9)
      Includes correspondence from: Thasitēs, Panos K.; Theocharēs, Giōrgos Ch.; Tsiampousēs, Vasilēs; Trivizas, Sōtērēs; Trypanis, C. A. (Constantine Athanasius); Tsianikas, Michalēs; Tropaiatēs, Alkēs K.; Triarchēs, Phōtēs; Taxiarchēs, Dinos.
    - Tasoulēs, Themēs, 1992-2005; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Themelēs, Geōrgios, 1949-1973; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Theodōrakopoulos, Loukas, 1955; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Theodōrou, Nellē, 1962-1981; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Theotokas, Giōrgos, 1964; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Thevaios, Geōrgios, 1986-1988; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Thoividopoulos, Dēmētrēs, 1971-2004; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Thrylos, Alkēs (Ouranē, Helenē), 1956-1965; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Tonnet, Henri, 2005; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Triantaphyllopoulos, N. D., 1975; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Tsakōnas, Dēm. Gr., 1985; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Tsaloumas, Dimitris, 1978-2008; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Tsiamēs, Chrēstos, 1995-1996; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Tsiampousē, Kaitē, 1968-1980; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Tsikritsē-Katsianakē, Chrys. (Chrysoula), 1994-1998; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Tsiropoulos, Kōstas, 1978-1996; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Tsopanakēs, Agapētos G., 1985-1990; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Tziovas, Dēmētrēs, 1987-1989; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - V (General), 1961-1989; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 28)
      Includes incoming correspondence from: Valetas, Geōrgios; Vavourēs, Stauros; Vrettos, Spyros; Hidryma Iōannēs kai Anna Vellidē; Vergēs, Anthēs; and Veloudēs, Dēmētrēs.
    - Vaianos, Marios, 1952-1974; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Vakalo, Helenē, 1988-1994; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Valaskantzēs, Dēmētrēs [Nea Synora], 1970; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Vamvakas, Petros, 1983-1991; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Vaphopouleio Cultural Center, 1991-2009; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Vaphopoulos, G. Th., 1926-1991; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Varverēs, Giannēs, 1976-2007; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Varvitsiōtēs, Takēs, 1958; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Vasilakakos, Giannēs, 2001-2005; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Vasilikos, Vasilēs, 1979-2005; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Vasilopoulou, Sophia, 1963-1993; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Vassēs, Kōnstantinos (Embassy of Greece in Tokyo), 1972-2007; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Veēs, Giōrgos, 1974-2006; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Veikou-Serametē, Katina, 1959-1981; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Veloudēs, Giōrgos, 1976-1982; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Venetēs, Thanasēs, 1984-1994; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Vistōnitēs, Anastasēs, 1972-2003; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Vivliothēkē tēs Voulēs tōn Hellēnōn [Library of the Hellenic Parliament], 1960-1998; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Vokotopoulos, Panagiōtēs L., 1974; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Votsē, Olga, 1963-1992; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Who's Who in the World, 1974-1995; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Xeinos, Giōrgos, 1971-1992; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Xephloudas, Stelios, 1958-1961; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Yiannopoulos, A. N. (Athanassios N.), 1978-2003; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Zades, Dēmosthenēs, 1958-1995; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Zakythēnos, Alexēs, 1975-1982; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Zēras, Alexēs, 1975-2007; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Zitsaia, Chrysanthē, 1953-1993; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - General, 1940-1956; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - General, 1957-1960; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - General, 1961-1966; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - General, 1964-1975; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 6)
      Includes congratulation letters on Alaveras's book Ho Hodostrōtēras. Correspondents included are: Renos (Apostolidēs, Renos); Anagnōstakē, Loula; Antōniadēs, Vyrōn; Chalvatzakēs, Manōlēs; Athanasoulēs, Kritōn; Chatzēpateras, K.; Demakēs, Mēnas; Galazēs, N.; Gialourakēs, Manōlēs; Glezos, Petros; Kaphtantzēs, Geōrgios; Karavias, Panos; Kotsiras, Giōrgēs; Kranakē, Mimika I.; Mourelos, Giōrgos I.; Meraklēs, Michalēs; Nikolaidēs, Melēs; Panagiōtopoulos, Iōannēs Michaēl; Pavleas, Sarantos; Pittas, Triantaphyllos; Politarchēs, G. M.; Peranthēs, Michalēs; Prasinēs, Phōtēs; Prevelakēs, Pantelēs; Samouēlidēs, Chrēstos; Spanias, Nikos; Roussos, Tassos; Spyridaki, Georges; Stergiopoulos, Kōstas; Theotokas, Giōrgos; Vakalo, Helene; Venezēs, Ēlias; and Zakythinos, Alexis D.
    - General, 1967-1969; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - General, 1970-1971; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - General, 1972-1974; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - General, 1975-1978; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - General, 1979-1980; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - General, 1981-1982; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - General, 1983-1984; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - General, 1985-1986; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - General, 1987-1988; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - General, 1989-1990; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - General, 1991-1992; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - General, 1993-1994; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - General, 1995-1996; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - General, 1997-1998; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - General, 1999; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - General, 2000; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - General, 2001-2002; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - General, 2003-2004; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - General, 2005; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - General, 2006; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - General, 2007-2010; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - General: Condolence Letters, 2007; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 9)
      Included are letters from several friends, colleagues, and acquiantances to Roula Alavera for the death of Tēlemachos Alaveras.
    - Copies of Letters, 1955-1990; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Unidentified, 1954-1998; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 1B: Works by Alaveras, 1942-2008; 8 boxes
    This subseries consits of autograph and typed manuscripts of Alaveras's earliest and latest writings.
    This subseries has been organized into books, diaries, and miscellaneous writings: the books have been arranged in an alphabetical order by the title of the work; the diaries and the miscellaneous writings have been arranged in a chronological order, starting with the earliest dates.
    - Books, 1952-2006; 3 boxes
      - Akriva gousta hē kyria, 2001-2006; 4 folders (Box 15, Folder 1-4)
        Includes autograph and typescript drafts, page proofs (first, second, and final editions), and printed material regarding the publication of the book.
      - Ap'aphormē, 1977-1990; 3 folders (Box 15, Folder 5-7)
        Includes galley proofs, autograph and typescript drafts, as well as printed copies of book reviews written by Michalēs Meraklēs, Anastasios Vistōnitēs, Kōstas Valetas, and Demētrēs Papakōnstantinou. There are also congratulation letters from several recipients of the book, including: Pantelēs Prevelakēs; Mēnas Dēmakēs; Phoula Lambelet; Zēsimos Lorentzatos; E.P. Papanoutsos; Tasos Korphēs; Helenē Vakalo; Nikos Karydēs; Apostolos Sachinēs; I.M. Panagiōtopoulos; Kōstas Stergiopoulos; Kritōn Athanasoulēs; Michaēl D. Stasinopoulos; Petros Glezos; Panos Karavias; Tasos Athanasiadēs; Phanēs kakridēs; Linos Politēs; Margarita Dalmatē; and the Ministry of Culture.
      - Gōnies kai opseis, 1982-1987; 2 folders (Box 15, Folder 8-9)
        Includes autograph and typescript drafts.
      - Gōnies kai opseis, 1985-1990; 2 folders (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
        Includes autograph manuscripts and printed copies of book reviews written by Thanasēs Geōrgiadēs, Giōrgos Veēs, Kikē Iōannou, and Michalēs Meraklēs. There are also thank you and congratulation letters from many recipients of the book.
      - Diēgēmatographoi tēs Thessalonikēs, 1952-1989; 2 folders (Box 16, Folder 3-4)
        Includes autograph manuscript drafts by Alaveras, Giōrgos Dellios, and Alkiviadēs Giannopoulos; page proofs of three short novels; lists with names of writers; a manuscript of an excerpt of a radio talk given by Takēs Gosiopoulos regarding Alaveras's book (15/12/1970); incoming correspondence; and the contract for the book rights.
      - Hoi alloi, 1970-1971; 2 folders (Box 16, Folder 5-6)
        Includes autograph and typescript drafts by Alaveras, and page proofs. There are also thank you and congratulation letters from many recipients of the book, including: Prasinēs, Phōtēs; Panagiōtopoulos, I.M.; Sinopoulos, Takēs; Vakalo, Helenē; Papatsōnēs, Takēs; Xephloudas, Stelios; Stergiopoulos, Kōstas; Peranthēs, Michalēs; Kontou, Nana; Dēmakēs, Mēnas; Glezos, Petros; Pentzikēs, Nikos Gavriēl; Giannopoulos, Alkiviadēs; and Pittas, Triantaphyllos.
      - Hōs kyliomenos tapēs, 1987-1997; 2 folders (Box 16, Folder 7-8)
        Includes autograph and typescript drafts with handwritten emendations and the story Archeion published in a book form by Paratērētēs, Thessalonikē 1987.
      - Me ton Barmpalia, 1965-1999; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 9)
        Includes autograph manuscript drafts by Alaveras and an issue of the magazine lagkadia, 8 (December 1996) dedicated to the poet Ēlias P. Katsogiannēs.
      - S'eutheia grammē, 1983-1991; 2 folders (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
        Includes Alaveras's autograph manuscripts of the diary he kept during his trip to Poland. There is also a separate folder with thank you and congratulation letters from the recipients of his book. Correspondents included are: Mētsakēs, Karolos; Pentzikēs, Nikos Gavriēl; Geralēs, Giōrgos; Athanasiadēs, Tasos; Kephalas, Ēlias; Makrēs, Solōn; Plōritēs, Marios; Glezos, Petros; Sarantē, Galateia; Plaskovitēs, Spyros; Kakridēs, Phanēs I.; Koutlēs, Thanasēs; Geranēs, Stelios; Vakalo, Helenē; Papakōnstantinou, Michalēs; Lampele Phoula; Mourelos, Giōrgos I.; Minōtēs, Alexēs; Zitsaia, Chrysanthē; Chatzēpateras, Kōstas N.; Markopoulos, [Giōrgos]; Vazra, Persa; Iōannidēs, I.D.; Anagnōstou, Tasos; Kaphtantzēs, Giōrgos, Skartsēs, Sōkratēs, and others.
      - Sēmeiōseis, 1952-2004; 2 folders (Box 17, Folder 3-4)
        Includes autograph manuscript drafts by Alaveras. Newspaper clippings from various local papers from 1965-1982 have been transfered in Box 43 (folder 1).
        In this folder is kept material that Alaveras put together with the drafts of Sēmeiōseis, such as page proofs and clippings of articles or essays published in several Greek literary magazines. Included are: "Skepseis ap'aphormē tis prozes tou Themelē hopou synantietai hyliko tēs poiēsēs tou" published in Ho poiētēs Giōrgos Themelēs: tomos timētikos, 1971; "Prōtes synantēseis" published in Nea Hestia, 1698-1699 (1-15 April 1998); "Thelō mia eikona" dated July 1, 1993; "Me tous planētas" published in Nea Hestia, 1403 (1985); "Amerimnoamerimnos" published in Kritikē parousia tou Petrou S. Spandōnidē, (1992); "Entechnos logos" publisehd in hē lexē, 144 (March-April 1998); "Diavazontas ton Ḏostogiephski tou Tasou Athanasiadē"; "D.K. Vogazlēs: henas machētēs tou Valkanikou hellēnismou" published in Nea Hestia, 1571 (Christmas 1992); "Arthra kai meletēmata gia tē zōē kai to ergo tou Paulou Papasiōpē" in Elimeiaka, 3; Tou Giōtamē in Aphierōma ston I.M. Panagiōtopoulo, 1988; and "Logotechnika themata" in Nearchos, 29 (October-December 2003); "Katochiko" (23.2.1989).
      - To rologi, 1957-1958; 2 folders (Box 17, Folder 5-6)
        Includes Alaveras's autograph manuscripts of his novel To rologi. There is also incoming and outgoing correspondence with Alaveras's friends and colleagues, including: Sphakianakēs, Giannēs; Dēmakes, Mēnas; Thrylos, Alkēs; Sinopoulos, Takēs; Varvitsiōtēs, Takēs; Kotsiras, Giōrgēs; Athanasoulēs, Kritōn; Tsoukalas, Geōrgios, and the French Institute at Athens (Greece).
      - To sēmerino syngraphiko provlēma, 1961; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 7)
        Includes Alaveras's autograph manuscripts; Petros Spandōnidēs's review "Apopseis ap'aphormē to dokimio To sēmerino syngraphiko provlēma"; photocopies of printed reviews by Spandōnides; clippings; and incoming correspondence from Meraklēs, Michalēs; Panagiōtopoulos, I.M.; Kotzias, Alexandros; Athanasoulēs, Kritōn; and Glezos, Petros.
    - Diaries, 1983-1989; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 8)
      Consists of loose pages of autograph manuscripts of Alaveras's daily personal experiences, thoughts or feelings, including comments on current events. He also kept clippings of newspapers and other printed material that they were of his interest. The material is kept in the way Alaveras had organized it. A handwritten note on one of the discarded envelopes stated that all this material is unpublished.
    - Diaries, 1990-1998; 7 folders (Box 18, Folder 1-7)
      Same as above.
    - Diaries, 1999-2004; 6 folders (Box 19, Folder 1-6)
    - Diaries, 2007; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Writings, 1942-2008; 3 boxes
      - Biographical Statement, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 2)
        Includes typescripts with handwritten corrections by Alaveras and a few autograph manuscripts.
      - Early Writings, 1942-1945; 3 folders (Box 20, Folder 3-5)
        Includes autograph manuscript drafts of Alaveras's essays, short stories, and poems in Greek.
      - Early Writings, 1944-1968; 4 folders (Box 21, Folder 1-4)
        Includes autograph manuscript drafts of Alaveras's essays, short stories, and poems in Greek. Some of them were kept in a folder entitled "Kampanes. Pezographēmata." Included are: "Hoi Megalexantroi" dated 1947 and published in the magazine Morphes, 9 (January 1947); "Polemikē pezographia" dated 1952; "Ho dromos mas. Se eikones pente pente skēnes" dated 1945; "Narkalieutēs"; "Phantastikes phōnes" dated 1949; "Henas logos me logikē kai chōris logikē" dated 1949; "T'agrimia tou allou dasous" dated 1950; "Hē pneumatikē Thessalonikē tou 1952"; a notebook with a novel entitled " Sta skotadia tēs Tsouka-Rōssa" dated 1952; "Pera apo to sēmeio stērigmatos" dated 1952. Other stories included are: "Moirolatrēs"; "To dentraki" dated 1944; "Ho mastro-Nikolas"; "Hagnē, Hagnoula"; "Gia to Mesolongi"; "To tēlephōno" dated 1944; "Hē emporissa"; and many others. There is also a small notebook dated 1962 and one folder consisting of undated early writings. Additionally, there are issues of the student magazine Pnoē/ 2-3, 6-7, where Alaveras published some of his earliest writings dated 1944-1945.
      - Later Writings, 1975-2002; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 5)
        Includes autograph manuscript drafts of Alaveras's short stories: "Arta Kor"; "Napoleōn"; "Grammata Verenikēs"; "Eukaireies"; "Gephyrōsē tou chronikou chasmatos," and "Amixia";"K' hoi treis"; "Aeropetamata" or "Eis ton kairon" an excerpt of the unpublished Pessoi.
      - Ta logotecnhika periodika tēs Thessalonikes (1889-1954). Symvolē stēn historia kai to periochomeno tous., 1952-1986; 2 folders (Box 21, Folder 6-7)
        Includes a study that Alaveras's prepared on the literary magazines of Thessalonikē from 1889 to 1955. Included are autograph and typescript drafts; a copy of the by-laws of the magazine Morphes dated 1952) and two essays entitled: "Typographeia kai ephēmerides tēs Thessalonikēs" and "Ta logotechnika periodika kai vivlia tēs Thessalonikēs" by Vasileios G. Aidalēs, both dated 1974. Roula Alavera's note on the discarded envelope stated that this was a personal study by Alaveras.
      - Student Notes, 1942-1944; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Miscellaneous Notes, 1969-2005; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 2)
        Includes autograph manuscript notes and thoughts by Alaveras. Roula Alaveras's note on the discarded evelope stated: "There are notes that were used for Alaveras's novels or intended for future publication."
      - Notes on Nea Poreia, 1979-2002; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Undated Notes, 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 1C: Talks; Questionnaires; Radio Broadcasts; TV Series; and Interviews, 1947-2006; 2 boxes
    Includes autograph and typescript drafts of several talks, interviews, TV series, and radio broadcasts that Alaveras's delivered through the years.
    This subseries has been arranged by type of material.
    - Talks, 1947-1994; 1 box
      - "Skepseis gia tē neōterē pezographia"; "Taxidi stēn Ēpeiro"; "Neohellēnikē logotechnia; and Miscellaneous, 1947-1989; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 5)
        Includes a talk that was given by Alaveras at the Chamber of Commerce and Industry of Thessalonikē. There are also loose sheets with undated notes.
      - "Ti epiphylassei to mellon", 1978 December 17; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - "Hē logotechnia tēs Thessalonikēs ston aiōna mas", 1993-1994; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 7)
        Includes a talk that was given at the Supreme War College.
      - "Dēm. St. Dēmou-Anekdota phylla hēmerologiou", 1993; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 8)
        Includes a draft and miscellaneous notes of Alaveras's presentation at the Hetairia Logotechnōn Thessalonikēs. There is also a copy of a list of Dēmou's translated works compiled by Philēmōn Paiōnidēs.
    - Interviews, 1963-2006; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 9)
      Includes autograph and typescript drafts, as well as some clippings of interviews given by Alaveras to several Greek literary magazines and newspapers. There is also an issue of the magazine Nea epochē, 4-5, July-August 1964.
    - Questionnaires, 1967-1986; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Questionnaires, 1976-1978; 1 folder (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Radio Broadcasts, 1956-1965; 1 box
      - "Pōs eidan hoi logotechnes ton topo mas", 1956-1957; 1 folder (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - "Provlēmata kai apopseis", 1956; 1 folder (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - "Taxidia stēn Hellada; "Anthrōpoi kai zōe"; "Hellēnikē pezographia", 1956-1965; 1 folder (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - TV Series: Hē Thessalonikē diēgeitai: "To pro-po", 1996; 1 folder (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 1D: Conferences and Meetings; European Programs, 1953-2003; 3 boxes
    This subseries consists of autograph manuscripts and typescripts, as well as some printed material regarding international or local conferences, meetings, symposia, and European programs.
    This subseries has been organized in a chronological order.
    - Conferences-Meetings, 1953-2010; 2 boxes
      - International Conferences on Palamas, Athens, 1953-2003; 2 folders (Box 23, Folder 6-7)